so in college i was a government major
which means i had to write a lot of papers
now when a normal student writes a paper
they might spread the workout a little like this
so you know you get started maybe a little slowly
but you get enough done in the first week
that with some heavier days later on
everything gets done things stay civil
and i would want to do that like that
that would be the plan
i would uh i would have it all ready to go
but then then then actually the people would
would come along and then i would kind of do this
and that would happen every single paper
but then came my ninety page senior thesis paper
you're supposed to spend a year on
i knew for a paper like that
my normal work flow was not an option
it was way too big a project
so i planned things out and i decided
it kind of had to go something like this
this is how the year would go
so i'd start off light and i'd bump it up
in the middle months and then at the end
i would kick it up into high gears
took a little staircase
how hard could you just walk up the stairs
no big deal right
but then funniest thing happened
those first few months they came and went
and i i couldn't quite do stuff
so we had an awesome new revised plan
and then but then those middle months
actually went by and i didn't really write words
and so we were here and then two months
turned into one month she turned into two weeks
and one day i woke up with three days
until the deadline still not having written a word
and so i did the only thing i could
i wrote ninety pages over seventy two hours
pulling not one but two all nighters
humans are not supposed to pull two all nighters
sprinted across campus dove in slow motion
and guided in just of the deadline
and i thought that was the end of everything
but a week later i get a call
it's the school and they say is this tim urban
and i say yeah and they say we need to talk
about your thesis and i say okay
and they say it's the best one we've ever seen
a that did not happen it was a very very bad thesis
i just wanted to enjoy that one moment
when all of you thought this guy is amazing
no no it was very very bad
anyway today i'm a writer blogger guy
i write the blog weight but why
and a couple of years ago i decided
to write about procrastination
my behavior is always perplexed
the non procrastinators around me
and i wanted to explain to the non procrastinators
of the world what goes on in the heads
of procrastinators and why we are the
where we are now at a hypothesis
that the the brains of procrastinators
were actually different than the brains
of other people and to test this
i found an mri lab that actually let me scan
both my brain and the brain of a proven non procrastinator
and i and so i could compare them
and i actually brought them here to show you today
and i want you to take a look carefully
to see if you can notice a difference
and i know that if you're not a trained brain expert
it's not that obvious but just take a look
okay so here's the brain of a non procrastinator
哈哈哈哈now here's my brain
哈哈哈哈there is a difference
both brains have a rational decision maker in them
but the procrastinator's brain also has
an instant gratification monkey
now what does this mean for the procrastinator
well means everything's fine until this happens
so the rational decision maker will make
the rational decision to do something productive
but the monkey doesn't like that plan
so he she takes the wheel and he says
actually let's read the entire wikipedia page
of the nancy kerrigan tanya harding scandal
because i just remember that that happened
then we're gonna go over to the fridge
we're gonna see if there's anything new in there
since ten minutes ago after that
we're gonna go on a youtube spiral
that starts with videos of richard feynman
talking about magnets and ends much much later
with us watching interviews with justin bieber's mom
all that's gonna take a while
so we're not gonna really have room
on the schedule for any work today sorry
now what is going on here
the instant gratification monkey does not seem
like a guy you want behind the wheel
he lives entirely in the present moment
he has no memory of the past
no knowledge of the future
and he only cares about two things
easy and fun now in the animal world
that works fine if you're a dog
and you spend your whole life doing nothing
other than easy and fun things
you're a huge success and to the monkey
humans are just another animal species
is to keep well slept well fed
and propagating into the next generation
which in tribal times might have worked okay
but if you haven't noticed now
we're not in tribal times
we're in an advanced civilization
and the monkey does not know what that is
which is why we have another guy in our brain
the rational decision maker who gives us
the ability to do things no other animal can do
we can visualize the future
we can see the big picture
we can make long term plans
and he wants to take all of that into account
and he wants to just have us do
whatever makes sense to be doing right now
now sometimes it makes sense to be doing things
that are easy and fun like when you're having dinner
or going to bed or enjoying well
or in leisure time that's why there's an overlap
sometimes they agree but other times
it makes much more sense to be doing things
that are harder and less pleasant
for the sake of the big picture
and that's when we have a conflict
and for the procrastinator that conflict tends to end
a certain way every time
leaving him spending a lot of time
in this orange zone an easy and fun place
that's entirely out of the makes sense circle
i call it the dark playground
the dark playground is a place that all of you
procrastinators out there know very well
it's where leisure activities happen
at times when leisure activities are not supposed to be happening
the fun you have in the dark playground
isn't actually fun because it's completely unearned
and the air is filled with guilt dread anxiety
self hatred all those good procrastinator feelings
and the question is in this situation
with the monkey behind the wheel
how does the procrastinator ever get himself
over here to this blue zone
a less pleasant plates but were really important things happen
well it turns out that the procrastinator
has a guardian angel someone who's always looking down
on him and watching over him in his darkest moments
someone called the panic monster
the panic monster is dormant most of the time
but he suddenly wakes up any time a deadline
gets too close or there's danger of public embarrassment
a career disaster or some other scary consequence
and importantly he's the only thing
that the monkey is terrified of
now he became very relevant in my life pretty recently
because people of ted reached out to me
about six months ago and invited me to do a ted talk
now of course i said yes it's always been a dream of mine
to have done a ted talk in the past
but in the middle of all this excitement
the rational decision makers seemed to have something else
in his mind he was saying we clear on what we just accepted
do we do we get what's going to be now happening
one day in the future we need to sit down
and work on this right now
and the monkey said totally agree
but also let's just open google earth
and lizom into the bottom of india
like two hundred feet above the ground
and we're gonna scroll up two and a half hours
till we get to the top of the country
so we can get a better feel for india
哈哈哈哈so that's what we did
that day has six months turned into four
and then two and then one
the people of ted decided to release the speakers
and i opened up the website
and there was my face staring right back at me
and guess who woke up
so the panic monster starts losing his mind
and a few seconds later the whole systems in mayhem
and the monkey who remember he's terrified of the panic monster
boom he's up the tree and finally finally
the rational decision maker can take the wheel
and i can start working on the talk
now the panic monster explains all kinds of pretty insane
procrastinated behavior like how someone like me
could spend two weeks unable to start the opening sentence
of a paper and then miraculously find
the unbelievable work work ethic to stay up up all night
and write eight pages and this entire situation
with the three characters this is the procrastinator system
it's not pretty but in the end it works
and this is what i decided to write about
on the blog just a couple of years ago
now when i did i was amazed by the response
literally thousands of emails came in
from all different kinds of people
from all over the world doing all different kinds of things
these are people who were nurses and bankers
and painters and engineers and lots and lots of ph d students
and they were all writing saying the same thing
i have this problem too but what struck me
was the contrast between the light tone of the post
and the heaviness of these emails
these people were writing with intense frustration
about what procrastination had done to their lives
about what this monkey had done to them
i thought about this and i said
what the procrastinator system works
then what's going on why are all these people
in such a dark place well it turns out
that there's two kinds of procrastination
everything i've talked about today
the examples i've given they all have deadlines
and when there's deadlines the effects of procrastination
are contained to the short term
because the panic monster gets involved
but there's a second kind of procrastination
that happens in situations when there is no deadline
so if you want to have a career
you want to be a self starter
something in the arts something entrepreneurial
there's no deadlines on those things at first
because nothing's happening at first
not until you've gone out and done the hard work
to get some momentum to get things going
there's also all kinds of important things
outside of your career that don't involve any deadlines
like seeing your family or exercising
and taking care of your health
working on your relationship or getting out of a relationship
that isn't working now if procrastinator is only mechanism
of doing these hard things is the panic monster
that's a problem because in all of these non deadline situations
the panic monster doesn't show up
there's nothing to wake up for
so the effects of procrastination they're not contained
they just extend outward forever
and it's this long term kind of procrastination
that's much less visible and much less talked about
than the funnier short term deadline based kind
it's usually suffered quietly and privately
and it can be the source of a huge amount
of long term unhappiness and regrets
and i thought you know that's why these people
are emailing and that's why they're in such a bad place
it's not that they're craming for some project
it's that long term procrastination has made them feel
like a spectator at times in their own lives
you know the frustration was not that they couldn't achieve
their dreams is that they weren't even able
to start chasing them so i read these emails
and i had a little bit of an epiphany
that i don't think non procrastinators exist
that's right i think all of you are procrastinators
now you might not all be a mess like some of us
and some of you may have a healthy relationship
with deadlines but remember the monkey's sneakiest trick
is when the deadlines aren't there
now i want to show you one last thing
i call this a life calendar
that's one box for every week of a ninety year life
that's not that many boxes especially since
we've already used a bunch of those
so i think we need to all take a long hard look
at that calendar we need to think about
what we're really procrastinating on
because everyone is procrastinating on something in life
we need to stay aware of the instant gratification monkey
that's a job for all of us
and because there's not that many boxes on there
it's a job that should probably start today
well i mean not today but you know sometime soon
thank you