it's funny the things you forget
i uh i won't see my mother the other day
and she told me this story
that i i completely forgotten about
how when we were driving together
she would pull the car over
and by the time she got out the car
and gone round the car to let me out the car
i would have already got out the car
and pretended to have died
哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈
because that's how you die
and i remember that was uh
that was a game i used to play
with myself to entertain myself
whenever i was bored or or frustrated
settle down people say
we live in an age of information overloaded
right i don't know about that
but i just know that i get too many marketing emails
i got ua marketeamer from a ua supermarket firm
which uh will remain nameless
for predominantly legal reasons
but which i'm gonna call uh safe mart
i got anymore from them
and it said it well like this
it said um just three weeks until safe marked
at king's cross opens
and i resented this
because not only do i not remember signing up to that
but i i resent the fact that there
they appear to think that i should be excited
about a shop opening
so what i did is i um
i scroll down to the bottom of the email
and i pressed unsubscribed
and i thought that would be the end of it
but a week later i got another one
that said just two weeks until safe martyking's cross opens
i thought well obviously i haven't clicked hard enough
right so i i tried it again
right low and behold the week passes
you guessed it just one week until safe martyking's cross opens
and here's the problem
the internet gave us access to everything
but it also gave everything access to us
you know i i think right
it's hard enough to discriminate between the things
that genuinely matter in this world
and you know the minishi of life
without having emails about supermarket chains
and candy crush saga
and i was really annoyed with them
and i thought okay i should just
i was about to write a strongly word email
so i can do quite well
and i thought no i'm gonna find the game
so i replied to it
and i said i literally cannot wait
what do you need from me
they go back to me it's sky called dan
said hi james have asked the colleague
to help me with your query
like it needs help
i said what's the plan then
i'm thinking fireworks bouncy castle
i'm not sure what you mean
i said i'm just tremendously excited about the opening
do you want to put the bouncy castle or shi
he said i i think you have misunderstood
a new store is opening
but there is no celebration plan
i said but what was all the three weeks until
two weeks until emails
i was getting excited
i'm sorry you're disappointed
i said not to worry let's do something anyway
besides the deposit on the bounty castle
was not refundable if we don't use it
we're out a few hundred quid
dan he said mr vitchi not responsible
for anything you have ordered
i said let's not get into who did what
bottom line you and i are in this together
question would you be there
to make sure people take their shoes off
and i'll be honest uh
then my relationship with dan deteriorated somewhat
because the next email i got was this
thanks to emo your case number is
oh it's outrageous i said dan
and i go and i was just like this is all right
and i i i said dann
and he just it just kept kept up
and i thought this is terrible
i'm doing is collecting case numbers
i said i said d dog the store is now open
i said but danny must have wonder
why there was no patty castle
and then we were back to this
and that might have been the end of the story
but i remember that anything everything
even something as mundane as getting out of a car
can be fun if you find the right game
so this is what i applied
and we just uh we like we were dancing
it was just a beautiful relationship
we just kept kept going
and it was it was it was lovely
but to be honest guys
it was quite labor intensive
and um you know i had other stuff to do
believe it or not
and so uh why did i have a little uh
i have a little um uh email auto replier program
and what i do is i set it up
so every time it receives an email from safe mit
just pings one back right
so i set it up and it says
thanks to emo your case number is
and then it has a little formula that i wrote
uh to up the case number every time
and i put it on the server and said it running
i'll i'll be honest guys
then then i forgot about it
i check back on it the other day
uh i appears um there being a number of emails going
uh back and we're on twenty one thousand four hundred
it gives me an immense sense of satisfaction
to know that these computer programs
are just gonna be pinging one another
you know for for eternity
and his legacies go
i don't i don't think that's bad
so guys just remember right
if you ever you feel weighed down by the
you know the bureaucracy and often mdanity of modern life
don't fight the frustration
let it be the catalyst for whimsy
哈哈哈哈哈哈
thank you