so in college i was a government major
which means i had to write a lot of papers
now when a
normal student writes a paper they might spread the workout a little like this
so you know you
get started maybe a little slowly but you get enough done in the first week
that with some heavier days later on everything gets done
things stay civil and i would want to do that like that
that would be the plan i would uh i would have it all ready to go
but then then then actually the people would would come along
and then i would kind of do this and that
would happen every single paper
but then came my ninety page senior thesis paper
you're supposed to spend a year on
i knew for a paper like that my normal work flow was not an option
it was way too big a project
so i planned things out and i decided it kind of had to go
something like this this is how the year would go
so i'd start off light and i'd bump it up in the middle months
and then at the end i would kick it up into high gears
took a little staircase how hard could you just walk up the stairs
no big deal right
but then funniest thing happened those first few months
they came and went and i i couldn't quite do stuff
so we had an awesome new revised plan
and then but then those middle months actually went by
and i didn't really write words
and so we were here and then two months turned into one month
she turned into two weeks and one day
i woke up with three days until the deadline
still not having written a word
and so i did the only thing i could
i wrote ninety pages over seventy two hours
pulling not one but two all nighters
humans are not supposed to pull two all nighters
sprinted across campus dove in slow motion
and guided in just of the deadline
and i thought that was the end of everything
but a week later i get a call
it's the school and they say is this tim urban
and i say yeah
and they say we need to talk about your thesis
and i say okay
and they say it's the best one we've ever seen
a that did not happen
it was a very very bad thesis
i just wanted to enjoy that one moment
when all of you thought this guy is amazing
no no it was very very bad anyway
today i'm a writer blogger guy
i write the blog weight but why
and a couple of years ago i decided to write about procrastination
my behavior is always perplexed
the non procrastinators around me
and i wanted to explain to the non procrastinators
of the world what goes on in the heads of procrastinators
and why we are the where we are now
at a hypothesis that the the brains of procrastinators
were actually different than the brains of other people
and to test this i found an mri lab
that actually let me scan both my brain
and the brain of a proven non procrastinator
and i and so i could compare them
and i actually brought them here to show you today
and i want you to take a look carefully
to see if you can notice a difference
and i know that if you're not a trained brain expert
it's not that obvious
but just take a look okay
so here's the brain of a non procrastinator
哈哈哈哈
now here's my brain 哈哈哈哈
there is a difference
both brains have a rational decision maker in them
but the procrastinator's brain also has an instant gratification monkey
now what does this mean for the procrastinator
well means everything's fine until this happens
so the rational decision maker will make the rational decision
to do something productive
but the monkey doesn't like that plan
so he she takes the wheel
and he says actually let's read the entire wikipedia page
of the nancy kerrigan tanya harding scandal
because i just remember that that happened
then we're gonna go over to the fridge
we're gonna see if there's anything new in there
since ten minutes ago
after that we're gonna go on a youtube spiral
that starts with videos of richard feynman talking about magnets
and ends much much later with us watching interviews
with justin bieber's mom
all that's gonna take a while
so we're not gonna really have room on the schedule
now what is going on here
the instant gratification monkey does not seem like a guy you want behind the wheel
he lives entirely in the present moment
he has no memory of the past
no knowledge of the future
and he only cares about two things
easy and fun
now in the animal world
that works fine if you're a dog
and you spend your whole life doing nothing other than easy and fun things
you're a huge success
and to the monkey
humans are just another animal species
is to keep well
slept well
fed and propagating into the next generation
which in tribal times
might have worked okay
but if you haven't noticed
now we're not in tribal times
we're in an advanced civilization
and the monkey does not know what that is
which is why we have another guy in our brain
the rational decision maker
who gives us the ability to do things
no other animal can do
we can visualize the future
we can see the big picture
we can make long term plans
and he wants to take all of that into account
and he wants to just have us do whatever makes sense
to be doing right now
now sometimes it makes sense
to be doing things that are easy and fun
like when you're having dinner
or going to bed
or enjoying well
or in leisure time
that's why there's an overlap
sometimes they agree
but other times it makes much more sense
to be doing things that are harder and less pleasant
for the sake of the big picture
and that's when we have a conflict
and for the procrastinator
that conflict tends to end a certain way
every time
leaving him spending a lot of time
in this orange zone
an easy and fun place
that's entirely out of the makes sense circle
i call it the dark playground
the dark playground is a place
that all of you procrastinators out there
know very well
it's where leisure activities happen
at times when leisure activities
are not supposed to be happening
the fun you have in the dark playground
isn't actually fun
because it's completely unearned
and the air is filled with
guilt dread anxiety
self hatred
all those good procrastinator feelings
and the question is
in this situation
with the monkey behind the wheel
how does the procrastinator ever get himself
over here to this blue zone
a less pleasant plates but were really important things happen
well it turns out that the procrastinator has a guardian angel
someone who's always looking down on him
and watching over him
in his darkest moments
someone called the panic monster
the panic monster is dormant
most of the time
but he suddenly wakes up
any time a deadline gets too close
or there's danger of
public embarrassment
career disaster
or some other scary consequence
and importantly
he's the only thing that the monkey is terrified of
now he became very relevant in my life
pretty recently
because people of ted reached out to me
about six months ago
and invited me to do a ted talk
now of course i said yes
it's always been a dream of mine
to have done a ted talk
in the past
but in the middle of all this excitement
the rational decision makers
seemed to have something else in his mind
he was saying
we clear on what we just accepted
do we
to sit down and work on this right
totally agree but also let's just open google earth and